

Časlav Lazić

Profile

Highly responsible, also has exceptional diplomatic and negotiating skills, altogether a good communicator.

Pragmatic and loyal in teamwork.

Exceptional organizational skills, leadership qualities, good experience in project management.

Learns quickly, interprets information accurately, good problem-solving skills.

Easily adaptable to new working environments, cooperative and open-minded.

Employment History

Editor in chief, Glas javnosti, Belgrade

JULY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Manager of any print or digital publication, from physical newspapers to online magazines. Determine the look and feel of the publication, has the final word in what is published and what isn't, and leads the publication's team of editors, copy editors, and writers.

Editor in chief (World news edition), Medijska mreža, Belgrade

JUNE 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Editing and publishing World news, interviewing the most influential political asters home and abroad, supervising the final design of pages

Journalist and TV presenter, Ringier Axel Springer, Serbia,, Belgrade

FEBRUARY 2016 - JANUARY 2017

Wrote and edited over 1000 articles on the latest economy, chronicle, IT, arts, and entertainment news, engaged in both domestic and worldwide topics. Writing and editing texts in short online videos. Interviews with the most prominent authorities and actors in the regional daily policy.

Liquidator's personal assistant, Slobodan Lazić, Belgrade

JULY 2012 - JULY 2015

Listing property, judicial correspondence, deadline statistics, law advisor, monitoring of company liquidation process.

Author, The Independent Journalist's Association of Serbia (IJAS), Belgrade, Serbia, Belgrade

MAY 2009 - AUGUST 2009

Researching and collecting materials regarding media coverage during the bombardment and writing a report on the matter. Also responsible for presenting the project on the tenth anniversary of the day the RTS building was bombarded.

Researcher, Impunity Watch, Belgrade, Serbia, Belgrade

FEBRUARY 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2009

Responsible for conducting over 50 interviews with Serbia's most influential people and for investigating the issue of impunity of crimes in post-war societies by comparing the social environment in Serbia and Guatemala. Report: "Action to combat, Impunity in Serbia, Options, and obstacles" February 2009 – September 2009

Details

Belgrade

Serbia

+381641295196

caslavlazic@gmail.com

DRIVING LICENSE

B category

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

01.05.1983

Belgrade

Languages

English

Russian

Serbian

http://www.impunitywatch.org/docs/BCR_Serbia_Serbian.pdf

Analyst, UNITED NATIONS, The International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY, Office of the Prosecutor, Analysis and Research team, formerly known as Leadership research team (LRT)), The Hague

JUNE 2008 - FEBRUARY 2009

Assigned to perform contextual research and analysis review various facets of the conflicts in the former Yugoslavia, including historical background, political structures, demographic changes and use of media

Researcher, Youth Initiative for Human Rights, Belgrade

JANUARY 2007 - SEPTEMBER 2008

Investigating on human rights violations. Interviews with victims.

Writing annual reports on human rights violations in Serbia.

Monitoring the implementation of the Law on Access to Public Information.

Organizing seminars

A representative for the Youth Initiative for Human Rights at the annual meetings of the OSCE in 2007, 2008, Vienna, and Warsaw.

Participant in a large number of abstracts on Human Rights held in the country and abroad.

Education

Junior Web Developer, CUBES, Belgrade

OCTOBER 2019 - MAY 2020

Junior Front End Developer

Skills: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, WORDPRESS

Master's degree, University of Belgrade, Faculty of Law, International Law, Belgrade, Belgrade

Graduate, First Belgrade Gymnasium, Belgrade

SEPTEMBER 1998 - MAY 2002